# Burhan Ahmad **Mudassar**

1002 State St. NW, Apt 3, Atlanta, GA 30318, USA

🛘 (+1) 404-944-6578 | 🗖 burhanahmadmudassar@gmail.com | 🎁 burhanmudassar.github.io | 🖸 burhanmudassar | 📠 burhan-ahmad-mudassar-88258a51

# Summary.

Graduate Research Assistant at GREEN Lab, currently working on a Ph.D under the supervision of Dr. Saibal Mukhopadhyay. My thesis is focused on smart cameras with integrated on-camera machine learning algorithms. 2+ years experience with Deep Learning Frameworks for Computer Vision. 3+ years experience in RTL design with Verilog. Interested in working in a cross-platform team focused on solving both hardware and software challenges.

# **Education**

## **NUST(National University of Sciences and Technology)**

**B.S. IN ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING** 

• Awarded Chancellor's Silver Medal for securing 2nd place within the batch

#### **Georgia Institute of Technology**

M.S. IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

· Specialized in VLSI

#### **Georgia Institute of Technology**

Ph.D in Electrical and Computer Engineering

High-level vision tasks for embedded platforms

#### Islamabad, Pakistan

Aug 2008 - Aug. 2012

#### Atlanta, GA, USA

Aug 2013 - May 2015

### Atlanta, GA, USA

Atlanta, USA

Atlanta, USA

Jan 2017 - PRESENT

Aug 2016 - Exp Aug 2020

# Work Experience \_

#### **Georgia Institute of Technology**

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

- Efficient Algorithms and Hardware for Deep Learning
- Deep Learning based Feedback control of Camera Parameters

**Center for Advanced Research in Engineering (CARE)** 

• Intelligent Applications and Enablers for Smart Cameras

#### **Georgia Institute of Technology**

GRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT

Conducted office hours and assignment grading for ECE 6122 – Advanced Programming Techniques with C++

Created assignments with autograding and conducted office hours for ECE 8813 – Adv. Digital Design with Verilog

# Aug 2016 - May 2017

#### Islamabad, Pakistan

#### SENIOR DESIGN ENGINEER

- · Development of Software Defined Radio Unit
- Hardware/Software Co-Design of waveform transceivers on FPGA+DSP
- Implemented CPM Coarse Timing Recovery, Carrier Phase and Frequency Offset Module in FPGA
- Implemented GMSK Frequency Hopping Modulator on TI TMS320C64X DSP

#### **Georgia Institute of Technology**

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

· Master's Thesis: Energy-Aware, Energy Efficient Moving Object Detection Module on FPGA

#### China Mobile Pakistan (Zong)

Operations and Maintenance for NSS Nodes including MSC, MGW, HLR

#### SR. OFFICER NSS

YouPark INTERN

· Created a Financial Management Application with OCR Receipt Scanning on the Android Mobile Platform

### **COGNET-SEECS (Cognitive Radio Research Group)**

Implemented tree based channel assignment algorithms in Network Simulator 2

May 2015 - July 2016

# Atlanta, USA

Jan 2014 - May 2015

#### Islamabad, Pakistan

July 2012 - Aug 2013

### Islamabad, Pakistan

Oct 2011 - Mar 2012

#### Islamabad, Pakistan

July 2011 - Aug 2011

#### **HSSD-SEECS (Hybrid Solid State Disk Research Group)**

Islamabad, Pakistan Jan 2011 - Feb 2011

Developed controller RTL for NAND Flash and MRAM chips in Verilog and implemented them on a Virtex 5 FPGA

#### AMSG-SEECS (Analog and Mixed-Signal Research Group)

• Developed Mouse and Keyboard RTL based firmware on Spartan II FPGA kit

Islamabad, Pakistan

Jul 2010 - Aug 2010

# Honors & Awards

2012	<b>1st place</b> , ICT-COMPPEC Digital Systems Category	Islamabad, Pak
2012	Best Industrial Project, NUST-SEECS Open House	Islamabad, Pak
2013	Gold Medal for Best Research Project, 6th UG Convocation NUST-SEECS	Islamabad, Pak
2013	Silver Medal for Securing 2nd Position in Batch, 6th UG Convocation NUST-SEECS	Islamabad, Pak
2013	Fulbright Scholarship, MS in ECE at Georgia Tech	Atlanta, USA

# Skills\_

- 1. **Programming Languages:** Python, C/C++, System Verilog, TCL
- 2. Pytorch/Tensorflow/Caffe 3. Cadence Virtuoso

# **Publications**

#### JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

1. Jong Hwan Ko, Mudassar, Burhan Ahmad, and Saibal Mukhopadhyay. An energy-efficient wireless video sensor node for moving object surveillance. IEEE Transactions on Multi-Scale Computing Systems, 1(1):7-18, 2015

#### **CONFERENCE PUBLICATIONS**

- 1. Jong Hwan Ko, Mudassar, Burhan, Taesik Na, and Saibal Mukhopadhyay. Design of an energy-efficient accelerator for training of convolutional neural networks using frequency-domain computation. In 54th ACM/EDAC/IEEE Design Automation Conference (DAC). IEEE, 2017
- 2. Ramyad Hadidi, Bahar Asgari, Mudassar, Burhan Ahmad, Saibal Mukhopadhyay, Sudhakar Yalamanchili, and Hyesoon Kim. Demystifying the characteristics of 3d-stacked memories: A case study for hybrid memory cube. In IEEE International Symposium on Workload Characterization (IISWC). IEEE, 2017
- 3. Ramyad Hadidi, Bahar Asgari, Jeffrey Young, Mudassar, Burhan Ahmad, Kartikay Garg, Tushar Krishna, and Hyesoon Kim. Performance implications of nocs on 3d-stacked memories: Insights from the hybrid memory cube. In IEEE International Symposium on Performance Analysis of Systems and Software (ISPASS). IEEE, 2018
- 4. Saibal Mukhopodhyay, Marilyn Wolf, Mohammed F Amir, Evan Gebahrdt, Jong Hwan Ko, Jae Ha Kung, and Musassar, Burhan A. The camel approach to stacked sensor smart cameras. In Conference on Design, Automation Test in Europe (DATE), 2018
- 5. Mudassar, Burhan A, Jong Hwan Ko, and Saibal Mukhopadhyay. An unsupervised anomalous event detection framework with class aware source separation. In IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP). IEEE, 2018
- 6. Mudassar, Burhan A, Jong Hwan Ko, and Saibal Mukhopadhyay. Edge-cloud collaborative processing for intelligent internet of things: A case study on smart surveillance. In 55th ACM/ESDA/IEEE Design Automation Conference (DAC). IEEE, 2018
- 7. Priyabrata Saha, Mudassar, Burhan A, and Saibal Mukhopadhyay. Adaptive control of camera modality with deep neural network-based feedback for efficient object tracking. In 15th IEEE International Conference on Advanced Video and Signal Based Surveillance (AVSS). IEEE, 2018
- 8. Mudassar, Burhan A, Priyabrata Saha, Yun Long, Mohammed F Amir, Taesik Na, Jong Hwan Ko, Marilyn Wolf, and Saibal Mukhopadhyay. A camera with brain - embedding machine learning in 3d sensors. In Conference on Design, Automation Test in Europe (DATE), 2019
- 9. Mudassar, Burhan A and Saibal Mukhopadhyay. Focalnet foveal attention for post-processing dnn outputs. In International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN), 2019
- 10. Taesik Na, Minah Lee, Mudassar, Burhan A, Priyabrata Saha, Jong Hwan Ko, and Saibal Mukhopadhyay. Mixture of pre-processing experts model for noise robust deep learning on resource constrained platforms. In International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN), 2019